Sasha Prokhorenko

+380 (98) 210 27 51 | <u>djminikin@gmail.com</u> | <u>http://minikin.me/</u> | skype: minikin.robotek

Professional Summary

Forward thinking & awarded iOS & IoT software engineer
2 years of experience in iOS development
5 years of development & delivery IoT projects for high-profile clients
Solid understanding of the full mobile development life cycle
Able to meet tight deadlines and delivers superior performance
Passionate about learning and trying new technologies

Experience

IOS SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SELF-EMPLOYED — 2014-PRESENT

- Shipped my own app to the App Store
- Architected and implemented iOS applications with Swift, MVC/MVVM, UIKit, NSOperation, CoreLocation, MapKit, Realm, CocoaPods, MapBox, Fabric, Travis...,
- Profiling and optimizing applications
- Backend infrastructure development, maintaining and REST API's integration with IBM Bluemix, Firebase and Parse.

RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT DIRECTOR, AIMBULANCE — 2010-PRESENT

Awarded the most effective digital agency in Ukraine.

- Delivered & developed IoT projects (software & hardware) from scratch for big clients,
- Responsible for R&D that expanded company technologies,
- iOS development : architected and implemented client/server application with Parse and Facebook integration,
- Optimised web production process & minimised risks,
- Supervised project production processes and coordinating software developers
- Technical consulting.

PROJECT MANAGER, BRAINBERRY — 2007-2010

Digital agency which provides complex digital campaigns for high-profile clients & launched a few start-ups.

- Delivered multiple websites for clients,
- Launched several web start-ups,
- Coordinating and monitoring work of software developers and third parties,
- UX design development and prototyping,

Skills

Swift - iOS SDK - Cocoa Touch - Xcode - CocoaPods - Realm - IoT - Python - REST - JSON - Arduino - RaspberryPi - JavaScript - CSS - HTML - WebSockets - Ubuntu/Debian - Git - Travis - Sketch

Education

National Mining University, Dnipropetrovsk (Ukraine) — Master of Engineering (M.Eng.), 2002 - Electrical Engineering Technologies/Technicians.